Chu Meng
초몽
Call the eldest son
첫째를 들라 하라
Father, why did you urgently summon me?
부황
Come
이리 오너라
My body
짐의 몸이
Is getting worse day by day
나날이 나빠지고 있구나
Father, what are you saying?
부황
Do you remember
기억하느냐?
When I fought back to the capital
그때 아비가 도성으로 돌아왔을 때
The first time you called me father
처음 날 아버지라 부르는 너에게
What did I promise you?
내가 무엇을 약속했는지 기억하느냐?
I said
아비는 말했다
To make you the king of the entire realm
너를 이 천하의 왕이 되게 해주겠다고
This, take it
이걸 받거라
Father, this
부황, 이것은...
Rise
일어나거라
You've managed court affairs for many years
네가 조정을 다스린 지도 여러 해다
I'll entrust Xuan Kingdom to you
선국을 너에게 맡기마
I'm at ease
이 아비도 그렇고
Your mother
네 어미도
Can also rest in peace
안심할 수 있을 거야
But
다만
I have one thing
아비가 한 가지
I need your promise
네 약속을 꼭 듣고 싶구나
If Father commands
부황의 명이시라면
Your son will obey
반드시 따르겠습니다
Your second brother is impulsive
네 아우는 무모한 면이 있지만
But
허나
He values family and state
집안과 나라를 소중히 여기고
Values loyalty and righteousness
정과 의리가 깊다
Now in the army
지금 군에는
Grand General Zu Yue is in command
조월 대장군이 자리를 지키고 있으니
The Second Prince is not your enemy
둘째는 너의 적이 아니라
He is your support, understand?
너의 조력자다
In my lifetime
아비는 평생
I've done many things that can only be kept in my heart
가슴에 묻을 수밖에 없는 일들을 많이 해왔다
Loyal ministers and good generals, I've sacrificed
충신과 명장을
Brothers
피를 나눈 형제에게도
I've also raised my sword against
아비는 칼을 겨누었단다
Even though we drove out Wuzhao and recovered Great Xuan
비록 오노를 몰아내고
Such things
그런 공으로
How can merits and faults cancel each other out?
어찌 죄를 모두 씻을 수 있겠느냐
Father
부황
Sheng'er
성아
I want all of this
아비는 이 모든 것이
To end with me
아비 대에서 끝났으면 한다
Our Sikong family
우리 사공가 사람들은
Must not shed Sikong blood again
다시는 사공의 피를 서로 묻혀서는 안 된다
I want you to lead the people
짐은 네가 백성들을 이끌고
Into a golden age
태평성대로 나아가
To be a perfect and wise ruler
흠결 하나 없는 성군이 되길 바란다
Your son
소자
Will not fail Father's trust
결코 부황의 중한 뜻을 저버리지 않겠습니다
Rise
일어나거라
Good son
장하다, 내 아들